고마워
Arab League is good
아량, 물건을 네 형에게 들켰어
Previous that large stock of goods your eldest brother knew
Had known, ?? can know?
들켰다고요? 어쩌다요?
You ask him
그에게 물어봐
He had very early known, the goods also took away
벌써 알고 있었어
물건도 가져 갔어
Arab League fine person?
아가는?
Also in goods warehouse
창고에 있어
My eldest brother knew I also have the share?
형이 내가 했다는걸 알아?
This I did not know
You should better go ask Arab League finely
그건 몰라, 아가에게 물어봐
Arab League is good
Matter your eldest brother since already knew
네 형이 알았으니
직접 가서 얘기하는게 어때?
We pass chat, how do you have a look?
I must first ask Arab League finely
먼저 아가에게 물어보고요
Now ?? manages? Uncle
이제 어떡하죠?
And so on Arab League good makes clear the matter said again
아량이 자세히 알아본 후에
결정하자
You are not must wash the hands?
손 씻을 거예요? 먼저 씻으세요
You first wash
Gentleman
선생님
Has borrowed, thanks
실례해요
You ?? can in here?
당신이 왜 여기 있지?
You are not the Arab League spring?
아춘 아냐?
You admitted mistakes the person, I was not
잘못 봤어요
Arab League is good, what matter?
아량, 왜 그래?
We meet in nine?
우린 만난 적이 있어
Your ?? such?
I with you said I am not
난 분명히 아니라고 했어요
She calls Arab League to be full
Goes in
그녀는 아옥이야, 들어가
Red monkey that sum of money was not you swallows?
홍후의 돈을 당신이 가로챘지?
What do you talk nonsense?
I understand, lunatic
헛소리하지 말아요, 미쳤군
Arab League is good, what are you doing?
무슨 짓이야?
Kumchon
Not your matter
당신과 상관없어
Any not my matter
Why doesn't have my matter?
왜 나와 상관없어?
Goes in
아옥, 들어가
알았어
Arab League fine, goes in calls Arab League good to come out
You are a not pin
넌 불효자야
Said you come back from the overseas
난 네가 해외에서 돌아온 뒤
Has a look you to be able to reform
마음을 잡고
이젠 착해진 줄 알았어
You have reform?
You do not have
그런데 날마다 나쁜 친구들과
Specially becomes friends with the at sixes and sevens person
Your mother
Only can become friends with these dubious people
어울리다니
The Arab League snow, the water end comes
아설아, 물 좀 갖고 와
Makes the blood stream blood drop, entire person entire hall
Such attractive?
알았어요
온몸에 상처를 입고
돌아오면 보기 좋겠어?
You thought
왜 그러는거니?
If compares with the old father
나처럼 되고 싶어?
In this Tian Liaokang
Who is most unsatisfied I
The Japanese government is most unsatisfied I
일본정부는 세상에서
날 제일 싫어했어
Said I am a hoodlum
내가 깡패라서 그런 거야
I am any hoodlum
하지만 난 깡패가 아냐
Has not been wrong, at that time
The Japanese government is most unsatisfied I
어쨌든 일본 정부는
날 싫어했어
I also am for our this village in
난 그 때 마을을 위해
Reduces big problems into little problems
The minor matter does not have
많은 일을 했었어
I cannot take others
Also cannot moisten others
하지만 남의 물건은
A grass does not take, a grass does not moisten
쌀 한톨도 안 가져갔어
Therefore various places brothers all support me
그래서 많은 사람들이 좋아했어
Like you like this, the proper way works you not to do
Specially makes the demons bad idea the matter
너는 매일 일은 안하고
나쁜 짓만 골라서 하니
Like you, is the brothers and sisters-in-law
네 부모나 형제들이
Is eldest brother
어떻게 얼굴을 들고 다니겠냐?
Your mother, is any eldest brother
Brothers' and sisters-in-law's duty you said?
He ?? can like this?
Does your mother
At that time everybody said clear
그 때 우린 합의를 봤었소
I ?? know them to be able like this
그런데 그가 이럴 수 있소?
You have not looked for them
이 일은 내가 처리하겠소
Certainly has looks for them
Everybody discovers, the matter says clearly
그럴 것 없소
모두 모여서 얘기해야겠소
Arab League Sichuan
아천!
Looks for gruff Ding, said I look for him
근정에게 내가 찾는다고 해
Hateful, acts unreasonably
Arab League fine, these Shanghai young how?
아가! 대륙놈들은 뭐하냐?
Has not seen the person
못봤어요
Does your mother
빌어먹을
Arab League is good like this
아량때문에 일이 터져서
The matter already were many
I all did not know ?? says
어떡해야 할지 모르겠소
Front here
Kumchon, does not see for a long time
What now is making?
Eldest child not in
What confesses?
Arab League picks the elder sister
아검누님
Everybody sits, everybody seat
You can suffice today to look for me
I am very happy
안녕들하시오?
오늘 여러분이 날 찾아와
Let me Arab League pick has the face very much
체면을 세워줘서 고맙소
The person said the day broken all may make up
아무리 어려운 일이라도
Now this opportunity
You also are know
서로가 타협하면 해결돼요
Moreover you together grow up since childhood
또한 우린 같이 자랐으니
Has any to haggle over well, the province is convenient
서로 양보하여 해결합시다
We kumchon first begin, is the comparison is not right
김전이 먼저 친 것은 잘못했소
But matter
하지만 일의 발단은
Is from nine red monkeys these days qualifications
Involves
홍후의 돈에서 시작됐소
Kumchon he said
김전의 말에 의하면 홍후가
The red monkey is thinks the pit he little brothers' money
부하들의 돈을 가로채
Kumchon collects for his little brothers
김전이 돈을 달라고 하니까
The red monkey does not put out
홍후가 거절하자 일이 터졌소
The matter only then occurs
Kumchon said like this also makes sense
김전의 말에 일리가 있소
Kumchon can act unreasonably with the others
김전은 딴 사람은 몰라도
Certainly to cannot lie to me
내겐 거짓말을 못하오
Now the red monkey person died all dies
지금 홍후가 죽어서
Also cannot come out kumchon the confrontation
김전과 대질할 수도 없는
상항이오
Also fights the murder
Male kills the pig on the picture to give a present give-and-take
그리고 싸움과 살인은
서로의 잘못이 커요
Has tea, with bitter edible plant... ...
자 차들어요, 어서 들어요
The speech said such many has not been useful
계속 말해봤자 소용없고
Now most important
Is these Qian Yao solves, relentless is in no way good
지금 중요한건 돈이예요
내 생각엔 나누는게 좋겠어요
Is divided three according to mine meaning
Your younger brother
문량과 김전에게 주고
Kumchon
The red monkey he the mother age was such big
Certainly must give him
또 홍후의 어머니에게
골고루 나눠 줍시다
Yesterday dispatch was clear his family
오늘은 문청의 집에 가느라
Passes the night in his family, the diary has not written
일기 쓸 시간이 없었다
Evening chats with his two sisters-in-law
또 밤에는 문청의
둘째 형수와 앉아서
Listened to her Shuowen clear childhood the matter
문청의 어렸을 때 얘기를 들었다
Two sisters-in-law said their brothers
형수는 그의 둘째형이
Two elder brother most can study
But, Wen Ch'ingtsui is intelligent
공부를 가장 많이 했지만
Two sisters-in-law said his body experience like this
Is the heaven is jealous
형제중에 문청이 제일
똑똑하다고 했다
His two elder brother goes to the southern coastal provinces to become a soldier
둘째형이 돌아오지 않아서
Has not come back
집안식구들은 포개했지만
The article was clear their whole family already to look
그의 형수는 매일 집을
깨끗이 치워놓고
Only some two sisters-in-law
Every day reorganizes the clinic ????
Syringe, needle
주사기를 자주 소독했다
Every day early morning all takes away the disinfection
Only has her to believe
Two elder brother certainly also safe lives
그녀만이 둘째형이
무사히 돌아올 거라고
One day can come back
굳게 믿고 있었으며
As soon as comes back, with before is same
돌아와서 옛날과 같이
Starts to see a doctor for the person
환자를 진찰하고
Opens the medicine, gives an injection
음악을 들을 거라고 했다
Listens to the phonograph record, to listen to Beethoven
울지 마라
문열어!
어서 문열어!
Eldest brother
형님
무슨 일이야?
Under building ???
You quickly run away
Outside the very many Ashan soldier must catch you
아산의 부하들이
형님을 잡으러 왔습니다
Does your mother, what do they grasp my?
왜 날 잡으려고 해?
You first run away said again
어서 피하세요
What matter?
왜 그래요?
Some people catch eldest brother, we had to walk
형님을 잡으러 왔어요
어서 가요
Walks
가요
Inside you go in
들어가 있어
What matter has?
무슨 일이오?
Searches for
수색해!
Some people reported confidentially your son is the traitor to China
당신 아들이 매국노라는
신고가 들어왔소
My son is the traitor to China?
내 아들이 매국노라고?
Some people reported confidentially
신고가 들어왔소
Some people reported confidentially is the traitor to China!
매국노라고 신고가 들어와?
Must take away asks clearly
그러니 일단 데려가서
조사를 해야겠소
당신은 내 아들을 잘 알면서
Your his mother
You all are eat the gruel?
매국노라고 해?
You work as in any to be long
신고가 들어왔소
In long is difficult to bear
Difficult to bear may the quality not divide
신고만 하면 매국노가 돼?
Some people report confidentially
Some people reported confidentially is the traitor to China
I am a hoodlum
신고를 받고 조사하는 거요
The Japanese time is seized closes has closed
난 일제시대때 깡패라서
잡혀간 적이 있었어
You should first look up clearly
먼저 잘 조사해보세요
Like this is called the traitor to China?
이렇게 쉽게 매국노가 돼?
We can look up
조사할거요
Can look up? What meaning is this?
그게 무슨 말이예요?
Like like this is the traitor to China
?? seizes
내 아들은 매국노가 아니야
Can look up clearly
조사해보면 알게 될 거요
Our fathers and sons are the hoodlum have not been wrong
우리 부자는 깡패였지만
Why works as the hoodlum?
Is not for maintain entire Zhuang-zi
Exempts is bullied Japan
마을 사람들을 일본인에게서
보호하려고 그랬던 거야
Like this is the traitor to China?
그런데 매국노라고?
Like this is the traitor to China
Then you also are the traitor to China
The adult, I reported confidentially to you
He also is the traitor to China
그럼 누가 당신을 매국노라
신고하면 당신은 매국노겠네?
내 아들은 매국노가 아냐
Some people reported confidentially is the traitor to China
Such traitor to China ?? seizes
Who deceives?
당신들이 잘못 안 거야
Wen Liang!
4th oldest of father's ygr brothers
어제 셋째 삼촌이
Why don't three uncles know
Yesterday is seized by the serviceman
군인들에게 잡혀갔어요
아버지도 잡아가려고 했지만
The soldier also seizes the daddy
다행히 도망치셨어요
Fortunately the daddy runs quickly
Only is the foot is injured
셋째 삼촌은 매국노라서
Heard the serviceman can come to seize
Is some people reported confidentially three uncles are the traitors to China
잡혀갔대요
Said he becomes a soldier in Shanghai
옛날에 일본인을 위해
Did for the Japanese have been very many
Frames the Shanghai people the matter
많은 사람을 해친 죄래요
Three uncles if really so
Also was must already not right?
만약 삼촌이 정말 그랬다면
그만한 이유가 있을 거예요
Mother said that, your Taibei friends are many
외숙모는 넷째 삼촌이
아는 사람이 많으니
Can look for the person which has the facial countenance
Tries to find solution to guarantee three uncles
그들에게 부탁해서
셋째 삼촌을 구하라고 했어요
The money all prepared
돈은 이미 준비됐어요
Asks 4th oldest of father's ygr brothers surely to have to contact as soon as possible
삼촌 부탁해요
Arab League snow
I knew
알았어
Your parliament Mr. Chen does there have?
진선생님에게 물어봐
Has any relations
We are must ask others
괜찮아, 제발 부탁이야
Why do you want to say like this
안될 것 같아?
알았어, 그렇다면 할 수 없지
Good, is good
You must say like this calculated
그래, 준비해 둘께
I can prepare
I knew
I can make one to take
외숙모, 손님이 오셨어요
Mother
00:20:42,333 -> 00:20:43,630
Uncle led the visitor to come
I come immediately
곧 갈께
문량을 살려주세요
The article good emitted?
Does not have, I want no problem
Hasn't emitted why ?
My friend inquired in Taibei
Nanjing comes news
Said the Taiwan person no longer uses
The traitor to China rule punish
Therefore I believe no problem
But has not issued before the order
Cannot emit
Returns must wait for period of time
No problem, everybody felt relieved
Gentleman you must help
선생님, 도와주세요
Calm 1.
전정해
진정해
I want to ask the friend to help in Taibei
제가 대북의 친구들에게
꼭 도와주세요
부탁해서
Looked can good earlier emit the article
문량이 나올 수 있도록
힘을 써보겠습니다
Otherwise like this
Troubles you to make a phone call to give him eldest brother
그의 형님에게 전화해서
자세히 설명 좀 해주세요
Says with him quite clearly
Good
그러죠
Troubles you to meet 24
여보세요? 24번 좀 부탁해요
그래요
Good, that asked
좋아요, 부탁드려요
고맙소, 고맙습니다
Thanks, thanks
How?
뭐라고 해?
최근 매국노에 대한
Says any present Taiwan
The traitor to China examines the austere rule to have to change
법이 바뀌었대, 빌어먹을!
Does your mother
법은 그들이 만드니까
The law they suppose in any case
Casual they turn turn fall
마음대로 하라고 해
Our main island person is most pitiful
우리 대만인이 제일 불쌍해
A Japanese, a Chinese
일본인과 대륙인에게
차례로 괴롭힘을 당하니
The numerous people eat, the numerous people ride
Nobody hurts
왜 그래?
형님이 오셨어요
무슨 일인데?
문량때문이죠
알았어, 이판 끝내고 갈께
어서 걸어
걸 사람이 아무도 없으면
내가 먹겠어
형님
Eldest brother
앉으시오
Comes, here sits
이 쪽으로 앉으시오
앉으시오
Sits
재밌게 놀고 있는데
Failure in politeness
You are playing the interest to disturb you
방해해서 미안하오
지금 문량이 잡혀갔소
We Arab League are good, now is grasped in the jail
당신들이 관청과 친한걸
I knew you quite are ripe with the institution
알고 있으니
Must ask you
이번 구정까지 나올 수 있게
Before looked can celebrate the new year to hit causes
힘좀 써주시오
Now, embarrassedly disturbs you
형님 말씀은, 미안하지만
지금 문량이 잡혀갔으니
Arab League was good is now seized
당신들이 구정까지
Eldest brother's meaning
Before the hope new year's celebration causes him
빼달라는 것이오
지금 아량에 대해서
They say the Arab League good matter
말하는 것이오
The hope can cause before the new year's celebration him
문량이 잡혀가?
What time Arab League is good is grasped?
I do not know
왜 난 몰랐지?
나도 몰랐소
I did not know
Arab League is good seized, we all did not know
문량이 잡힌 걸 우린 몰랐소
What has us to be allowed to help?
지금 알았으니 돕겠소
Does your mother, the matter all is you does
Also feigns ignorance
너희때문에 이렇게 됐는데
모른다고?
You are crying
조용히 해!
너 정신나갔냐?
Your brain has been bad?
Says with them that does any
그런 말을 왜 해?
Tells them
그들에게 말해
The courtesy I understand
난 예절을 알고 있어
돈을 준비했다고 해
The thing all prepared
우리 형님이 예절을 알아
My eldest brother said that, the courtesy he knew
돈을 준비했다고 하오
Thing in here
돈을 준비했답니다
미대!
Beautiful black eyebrow coloring
이쪽으로
Here
문량!
Wen Liang!
빨리 가서 약을 가져 와
A bit faster, takes the medicine
빨리 갖고 와!
Bowl with soupspoon
Wen Liang!
문량! 누가 이렇게 때렸어요?
?? makes into this?
비켜!
어서 의사를 불러와
Is called the guest doctor
Peaceful, do not have to cry
울지마, 네가 울면
You cry the matter ?? to do?
어떻게 치료해?
Peaceful
빨리 물을 떠와
Takes the water
Huian clinic
혜안 병원이죠?
Doctor in? Asks, please a bit faster
빨리 이쪽으로 와주시오
Pushes aside his mouth
입을 크게 벌려
?? flows that many blood?
왠 피를 이렇게 많이 흘렸어?
데리고 나올 땐 괜찮았는데
Bring back to well also
A vibration blood all spouted on the vehicle
차에서 갑자기 피를 흘렸어요
빌어먹을!
Does your mother
전화했어?
The telephone hit did not have?
Hit
I hit again
내가 했어
또 걸을께요
Again comes, pushes aside his mouth
빨리 오라고 해
여보세요, 병원이죠?
Helps me to meet the Huian clinic
Asks him to be quick 1.
빨리 오라고 해!
알았어요
여기 급한 환자가 있으니
빨리 와주세요
I did not know recently ??
요즘 잘 때마다 항상 꿈을 꿔
Sleeps frequently has a dream
어렸을 때 아버지가 날 전봇대에
Each time all dream
In childhood is tied up by my daddy in ???on
묶는 꿈을 꿨어
다 됐어?
The water rolled did not have?
다 됐어요
The water rolled
I remembered has a year
내가 어렸을 때인데
구정 며칠 전쯤이었어
Also is before the new year's celebration
아버지가 도박을 좋아해서
My father's young time likes betting very much
Quickly has celebrated the new year, in family not half minute money
집에 구정을 쇨 돈이 없었지
I mother have taken Jin Hsiang?
어머니께 금목걸이가 있어서
아버지더러 팔라고 했어
Is called me the father to take away works as
어머니는 아버지가 그 돈으로
I mother fear my father
When the money takes away the gambling
Is called me to go together with him
또 노름을 할까봐
나더러 아버지를 따라
가라고 하셨지
The result my the father money just attained the hand
아버지는 돈을 받자
날 전봇대 옆으로 데려가서
Deceives me to ???side
허리띠로 날 묶어놓고
또 도박을 하러 가셨어
The belt loosens ties up me in ???on
Own bet
In December the day good is cold
한창 추운 12월이었지
날이 어둡도록 사람이 없었어
Entire strip road all nobody comes
얼마 후 사람이 지나가다가
The quick darkness only then some people passed through
날 보고 풀어줬지
Looked I am tied up in there
Only then helps me to untie
난 그 때 얼어죽을 뻔했어
Is frozen almost dies
그 다음부터는 어머니가
Later my father will leave the gate to want to make any
I mother call me to go together with him
I all do not go
따라가래도 난 안갔어
대만 동포 여러분
Taiwan compatriot
27일밤 대북시에서
Taibei in day before evening
27 day and night in
큰 싸움이 일어나서
Because investigated the private smoke to injure accidentally the human life
많은 사람이 다쳤는데
This matter
우리가 모두 검거했습니다
I already handled
큰 싸움을 일으켜서
Apprehends smugglers the smoke accidental injury human life person
많은 인명피해를 낸 자들은
I already handed over the court strictly to interrogate
큰 벌을 받을 겁니다
Place by suitable penalty
그 때 부상을 입은 여자는
The woman which injures
다행히 상처가 크지 않아
The wounds condition is not certainly heavy
지금 치료중에 있습니다
But my already treated for her
And gives the comfort money
The width is beautiful, I wait the institutional records of a reign to hurry to Taibei
난 이번에 대북으로 가기로
했으니 잘 지내고..
Because why is reporter seized by the person
Left the matter
Today the radio said Taibei has the matter
오늘 라디오에선 대북에서
큰 사건이 있었다고 했다
The Taiwan person and the person from other provinces kill
대만인과 대륙인들이 크게 싸워
대북에 계엄령이 선포됐다
Taibei announces the martial law
병원에선 그 얘기를 하며
The hospital people all were saying this matter
전쟁이 방금 끝났는데
Everybody feared
A war just now ends
다시 터질까봐 두려워했다
Another war ?? can replace
오빠는 날 찾아와
Elder brother comes the hospital to look for me
문청과 대북에 간다고 했다
He and Wen Ch'ingyao goes to Taibei
이럴 때 가면 위험하지만
This time
Must go to the that dangerous place
꼭 가야한다는 걸 알고 있다
I knew they certainly have the matter to have to do
그저 걱정될 뿐이다
In the heart worried for them
Also does not dare to say the exportation
문청의 몸이 안좋다고
The article is clear his body not to be convenient
말을 못했는데
The elder brother you surely must look after
오빠가 그를 잘 돌봐주길
바랄 뿐이다
In where?
Kills the person from other provinces!
Stops, here is a hospital
Quickly comes in
This is a hospital, do not have to cause trouble in this
Asks, to look at my face
대만 동포 여러분
Taiwan compatriot
이번 사건에 대해선
About this event handling
어제 발표했으므로
I yesterday already have broadcast
잘 아실 거라고 믿습니다
You all should hear
Understands my meaning
우린 민심과 질서를
I now in order to stable will of the people
회복하기 위해
Rapidly restores the order
Makes a more spacious measure
특별히 몇가지 조항을
Announces several handling means specially again
발표하기로 했습니다
First, every participates in people of the this event
첫째, 이번 사건의 관계자들은..
정부의 과잉진압을 인정하여
The government reads its because impulse, deficient reason
죄를 추적하지 않겠습니다
?? leniently all did not investigate
둘째, 이번 사건에 검거된 자는
Second, because participates in this matter
Already personnel of by the military police arrest
모두 석방하여
?? the release
Delivers the military police the regimental head quarter
헌병부대로 보낼테니
집안식구가 와서
Gets back by its father and elder brothers or the family
신병을 인도하기 바라며
Needs long to release on bail by the neighborhood
복잡하게 이장들이
In order to avoid the procedure is troublesome
데려갈 필요는 없습니다
셋째, 이번 사건의 피해자는
Third, this casualties person
신분과 지위를 가리지 않고
Does not divide the government employees and teachers and the people
부상자는 치료하고
Not share this province person and person from other provinces
The wounded gives the treatment
The dead superiorly gives comforts and aids a bereaved family
사망자는 거기에 합당한
충분한 보상을 하겠습니다
넷째, 이 사건의 마무리를 위해
Fourth, this event how reconstruction
위원회를 구성하겠습니다
Specially sets up the committee
이 위원회는 정부 대표와
This committee eliminates the government personnel
Participates in government, the senator substandardly
국민의 대표로 구성하여
And supplements the from all walks of life people's represententative
각계 각층의 의견을 모아
In order to may hold the most people's opinion
국민의 뜻이 반영되도록
할 것입니다
왜 여기 계세요? 오빠는요?
You ?? in here?
Elder brother?
Doctor, quickly comes
선생님, 빨리 와주세요
빨리요
대만 동포 여러분
Taiwan compatriot
내가 계엄령을 선포한건
Yesterday I again announced the temporary martial law
여러분의 의견을 최대한으로
I this moment by extremely sincerity
Tells the most most good common people
수렴한 겁니다
난 여러분을 보호하기 위해
My announcement martial law
Completely is for protect you
계엄령을 선포했고
여러분은 절대 소문을 믿고
You surely do not believe evildoer's rumor
두려워해선 안됩니다
A little has doubts, is a little panic
법을 지키는 국민에겐
Regarding common people which obeys the law
아무 피해도 없을 것입니다
Certainly not slightly injures
You surely felt relieved
내가 다시 계엄을 선포한건
I therefore announce the martial law again
소수 난당들때문으로
Completely is for cope with
Certainly minority rebellious party rebels
누구세요?
이들을 빨리 없애지 않으면
They one day do not eliminate
여러분은 안심할 수 없습니다
The good compatriot, one day must be peaceful
문청은요?
암실에 있어요
문청씨
오빠는...
관영은 안전해
나 먼저 돌아가랬어
임선생님은 날마다
회의하러 가시고
대북에서 많은 사람들이 죽어서
민심이 흉흉해
정말이예요?
Is killed by the person is not?
Your where person?
당신은 어디 사람이오?
어디로 가시오?
Where person are you?
Where has to go to?
Taiwan person
대만인입니다
Where person?
어디 사람이오?
어디 사람이냐니까?
Where person?
This certainly is the Ashan person from other provinces
대륙 사람이 분명해
What do you have to do?
왜들 그러시오?
그는 귀머거리요
He is the deaf person
Eight years old heard
He with him said any he ?? hears
8살 때부터 귀머거리였소
문청씨
Wen Ch'ing
오빠, 어떻게 된 거예요?
Elder brother, you ?? like this?
Helps me to have a look the bone to have breaks
뼈가 부러졌는지 봐
I do not know
모르겠어요
참아요
임선생님은 실종됐고
Mr./Mrs. Lin is missing
위원회 사람들은 잡혀갔어
The processing committee's people are all seized
진의가 모두 잡아갔어
Chen Itiao soldier
A group seizes, a group kills
The proprietress, the young master came back
Came back
마님, 도련님이 오셨어요
You came back! Let me take on ??
오셨군요
In the family the military police, the police come daily
헌병들이 매일 찾아와서
왔구나? 많이 걱정했었다
대문이 다 떨어질 지경이야
The threshold all quickly stepped on puts down
정말 무서웠어
다리는 왜 그래?
Your foot was ???
왜 이렇게 심하게 다쳤어?
Wound such seriously?
왜 그러세요?
You ???
Came back well, you were are doing any
왜 다친 애를 때려요?
집에는 못있어, 어서 나가
In the family cannot live
You quickly hide to the in Laos go
The width is beautiful
관미는 집에서 못나가
You step all do not permit to exit
원장에겐 내가 말하겠다
Chief the that side I can write a letter with him say
아버지
3월 19일, 원장님이 내 짐을
In March 19, chief comes home
집으로 갖고 오셨다
All returns to my all things
아버지가 그렇게 하셨을 거다
This knew this is father's meaning
짐 속에는 아설의 편지가
Inside the baggage has an Arab League snow the letter
있었는데
문청이 임선생과 관계가 있다고
The article is clear seized by the serviceman
군인들이 잡아갔다고 했다
Said is with Mr./Mrs. Lin the related department
문청의 아버지는 귀머거리도
The article is clear his father to scold
잡아간다고
Also grasps including the deaf person
This does in society also have the natural justice
정부를 욕했다고 한다
난 그런 건 상관 안하고
The natural justice has altruism no matter
그저 문청이 어디 있는지
Now I only want to know
또 잘 있는지 알고 싶었다
Article clear other people in where
살아있으면 좋겠다
Is also safe lives
If lives is being good
오계문, 채동하 나와
Wu Chiwen, Cai Tung and, holds court
임문청, 나와
Lin Wench'ing appears in court
삼촌, 식사하세요
Uncle ate meal
너희들은 삶을 중요시해라
아버지는 죄가 없다
앉아요
이거 먹으면 안된다고
Uncle this cannot eat
I have spoken several with you
몇번이나 얘기했어요?
먹으면 안돼요
This cannot eat
문량씨
Mr. Wen Ch'ing
문청은?
The article is clear?
I did not know that, he yesterday exited
Has not come back to the present
몰라요, 어제 나가서
지금까지 안왔어요
네 아버지는?
Your father goes?
나가셨어요
Did not know that, he early morning exited